JESSE TUREK

eCommerce Professional Software Engineer

Brooklyn, NY, 11238

turekjesse@gmail.com

github.com/turekjesse

in linkedin.com/in/turekjesse

(609) 947-1416

jesseturek.netlify.app

CAREER SUMMARY

I am a Brooklyn-Based Software Engineer with five years of prior experience in eCommerce and a life-long passion for building, fixing, and tinkering with things. My knack for mechanics paired with my meticulous attention to detail and creative problem-solving skills were the driving forces that lead me to learn to code.

SKILLS









































PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE



Software Engineering Fellow

General Assembly

May 2021 - August 2021

- Learned programming and computer science fundamentals, as well as software engineering best practices in regards to full-stack development
- Worked collaboratively in an Agile development workflow using industry-standard version control tools to build full-stack applications

carbartt

Content Manager

Carhartt Work in Progress

March 2018 - May 2021

- Defined internal digital asset management workflows, best practices, and organizational structure using Dropbox Business
- Executed weekly site-wide content updates to align with sale performance, on-hand inventory, and marketing initiatives
- Coordinated with various internal teams to compile and maintain product data for 1000+ SKUs seasonally
- Bridged connections between various systems to accurately display essential product assets on us.carhartt-wip.com
- Designed and Built custom email marketing campaigns using Sketch and Mailchimp ESP
- Liaised with external agencies to implement site enhancements in an agile workflow
- Participated in the review and testing of new developments, designs, and features
- Reported weekly KPI's in regards to site user behavior and email marketing campaigns

Ecommerce Manager

Unis New York

November 2015 - December 2017

- Merged independent sales channels and inventory into one omnichannel platform (Shopify)
- Spearheaded complete web and mobile redesign of www.unisnewyork.com while meeting budget and deadline
- Achieved a 37% increase in revenue and a 17% increase in conversion from 2016 to 2017
- Streamlined end-to-end product launch and site merchandising process to offset production delays
- Reduced yearly operational costs by \$31,000

EASTERN MANNER Co-Creator

Passion Project

June 2010 - October 2017

Eastern Manner was conceived in 2010 as a creative outlet to test my woodworking and engineering skills, and ultimately attempt to bring something new to the skateboard industry. As Eastern Manner evolved into a small business, my interest in the digital world grew and sent me down a career path focused in Ecommerce, Digital Marketing, and Technology.

EDUCATION